Finding aid for the Xavier University President's Office records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
- 20th Century Xavier Presidents, 1901-2000
  - Paul O'Connor, S.J., 1955-1972
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Higher Education Assistance Commission, 1965-1967 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Memberships in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Research and Development Board, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Research and Development Board, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Research and Development Board, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Research and Development Board, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Research and Development Board (Foundation), 1964 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Research and Development Board (Foundation), 1964 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Research and Development Board (Foundation), 1964 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Research and Development Board (Foundation), 1965 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio College Association, 1955-1966 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      This is a folder containing various publications of the Ohio College Association.
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio College Association, 1967-1970 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      This folder contains various publications of the Ohio College Association.
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio College Association, 1963-1972 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Oversized Items:: Awards and Other Certificates, approximately 1955-1972 (Box 22-A)
      Housed separately in the Xavier University Archives.
    - Oversized Items: Personal Office Items, approximately 1955-1972 (Box 22-B)
      Housed separately in Xavier University Archives.
  - Robert W. Mulligan, S.J., 1972-1982
    - Inauguration and Biographical Information, 1971-2001 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1971-1973 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1981-1982 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Last Tango in Paris Controversy, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Last Tango in Paris Controversy, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Last Tango in Paris Controversy Newspaper Clippings, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Last Tango in Paris Controversy Newspaper Clippings, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Last Tango in Paris Controversy Correspondence, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Last Tango in Paris Controversy Correspondence, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Letters from Notables and Speeches, 1972-1978; undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Marx National Invitational Debate Tournament, 1973-1982 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Resignation, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Charles L. Currie, S.J., 1982-1985
    - Inauguration (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Speeches, 1982-1983; undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1981-1983 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1984-1986 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - President's Annual Report to Faculty, 1983; 1985 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Cardinal Joseph Bernardin, 1982-1985; undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
      This folder includes newspaper clippings also.
    - Correspondence with Fr. Edward Brueggeman, S.J., 1982; 1985-1986 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Students, 1981-1985 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Dr. Norman Francis, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Terry M. Grundy, 1984-1986 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with John P. Minahan (AVP), 1982-1986 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Bob Staak, 1979-1985; undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
      This folder does contain some correspondence which predates Fr. Currie's presidency.
    - Correspondence with Archbishop Desmond Tutu, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      This folder includes some periodical articles about Archbishop Tutu.
    - President's Discretionary Fund, 1983-1984 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - University Annual Budgets, 1983-1985 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Xavier Endowment, 1981-1983 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Xavier Endowment, 1983-1984 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Xavier Endowment, 1984-1985 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Xavier Commencement, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Marx National Invitational Debate Tournament, 1983-1984 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Receptions for Honor Students, 1983; 1985 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Edgecliff College, 1985-1986 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Carriage House Gallery and Art Collection, 1980-1981; 1984 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1983-1985 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Duffy & Shanley Public Relations (Athletics), 1983-1984 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Midwestern City Conference (Athletics), 1983-1984 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Midwestern City Conference (Athletics), 1985 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Services Employees International Union, Local 158A, 1982-1985 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Cancer Task Force (Cincinnati Chest and Council), 1982-1985 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Citizens Task Force on Cincinnati City Budget (Folder One), 1984-1985; undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Citizens Task Force on Cincinnati City Budget (Folder Two), 1984 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Citizens Task Force on Cincinnati City Budget (Folder Three), 1984; undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Citizens Task Force on Cincinnati City Budget (Folder Four), 1984-1985 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Frank Mastrianna (Interim), 1986
    - Correspondence and Various Documents, 1983; 1985-1986 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Albert J. DiUlio, S.J., 1986-1990
    - Inauguration, 1986, 1985-1986 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Inauguration, 1986 (Folder Two) (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Inauguration, 1986 (Folder Three) (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Inauguration, 1986 (Folder Four) (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1986-1990 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Speeches [and other papers] (Folder One), 1983; 1986-1987 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Speeches (Folder Two), 1987 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Speeches (Folder Three), 1988 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Speeches (Folder Four), 1989 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Speeches (Folder Five), 1990 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Commencement, 1989, 1988-1989 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Commencement, 1989 (Folder Two) (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Inauguration at Marquette University (1990), 1992 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Master's Thesis, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Michael Conaton (interim), 1991
    - Papers and Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Papers and Correspondence, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - James E. Hoff, S.J., 1991-2000
    Other items related to the Presidency of Fr. James E. Hoff, S.J. are housed separately in the Xavier University Archives.
    Six oversized displays from the funeral ceremony of Fr. Hoff: four poster boards (45' x 30") on rubberized backing; one framed collage of pictures and personal items related to Fr. Hoff; one additional frame collage of Fr. Hoff images. These items are housed separately in the Archives Map Case labeled "XUA-50, President's Office Records, James E. Hoff Funeral Artifacts.". These items were displayed in St. Francis Xavier Church during the funeral celebration for Fr. Hoff. The poster boards were made by the Xavier University Special Events Office. The framed personal items of Fr. Hoff were given to the university by the Hoff Family.
    The academic attire of Fr. Hoff is found separately housed in the Xavier University Archives and tagged "XUA-50, President's Office Records, James E. Hoff Academic Attire."
    - Biographical Information/ Newspaper Articles About Appointment, 1953; 1990; undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Inauguration (Inauguration Committees), 1991 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Inauguration (Mailing Lists, Lists of Guests), 1991 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Inauguration (Budgetary Matters), 1991 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Inauguration (Mass, Inauguration Ceremony, Reception), 1991 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Inauguration (Speakers, Reception and Dinner at Phoenix), 1991 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Inauguration (Invitations, Programs, Student Dinner, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Inauguration (President's Address, Photographs), 1991 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Clippings and press releases, 1990-2014 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letters of Inspiration, 1993-2000 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Doctoral Dissertation (Copy One), 1969 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Doctoral Dissertation (Copy Two, Part One), 1969 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Doctoral Dissertation (Copy Two, Part Two), 1969 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1991 February- July (Box 36, Folder 1-9)
    - Correspondence, 1991 July- December (Box 37, Folder 1-8)
    - President Clinton Visit, 1995-1996 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - President Clinton's Visit, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - President Clinton's Visit (1996) (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - President Clinton's Visit (1996) (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - President Clinton's Visit (1996) (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - President Clinton's Visit (1996) (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - President Clinton's Visit (1996) (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - President Clinton's Visit (1996) (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - President Clinton's Visit (1996) (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - President Clinton's Visit (1996) (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - President Clinton's Visit (1996) (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Speeches, 1991-2002 (Box 41, Folder 1-35)
      This box contains speech notes (and occasionally the typed speeches) of Xavier University President Fr. James Hoff, SJ. Speeches range from those given at academic awards ceremonies to end of the capital campaign in 2002. An index for each folder is included in folder 1.
      Speeches are arranged alphabetically by event or topic and then chronologically.
    - Speeches, 1991-2001 (Box 42, Folder 1-43)
      This box contains speech notes (and occasionally the typed speeches) of Xavier University President Fr. James Hoff, SJ. An index for each folder is included in folder 11.
    - Speeches, 1991-1998 (Box 43, Folder 1-11)
      This box contains speech notes (and occasionally, the typed speeches) of Xavier University President Fr. James Hoff, SJ.
    - Outside Organizations and Universities: Hebrew Union College and Hospice of Cincinnati, 1999-2004 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Outside Organizations and Institutions: Metropolitan Growth Alliance, 1998-1999; undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Outside Organizations and Institutions: Metropolitan Growth Alliance, 1999 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Outside Organizations and Universities: Metropolitan Growth Alliance, 1999 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Outside Organizations and Institutions: Metropolitan Growth Alliance and Holocaust Education Center: Hebrew Union College, 2000; undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Retirement from Presidency (December 31, 2000), 2000-2001 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      This folder contains the following content: 1. Announcement of the resignation; 2. Planning the resignation; 3. Public expressions of thanks; 4. Hoff named Chancellor of Xavier University (February 2, 2001).
    - Retirement from Presidency (December 31, 2000), 2000-2001 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      This folder contains letters of appreciation and thanks (part one).
    - Retirement from Presidency (December 31, 2000) (Box 46, Folder 3)
      This folder contains letters of appreciation and thanks (part two).
    - Retirement from Presidency (December 31, 2000) (Box 46, Folder 4)
      This folder contains expressions of appreciation.
    - Retirement from Presidency (December 31, 2000) (Box 46, Folder 5)
      This folder contains a scrapbook honoring Fr. Hoff and published by Xavier University.
    - Retirement from Presidency (December 31, 2000) (Box 46, Folder 6)
      Hoff Scrapbook published by Xavier University (copy two).
    - James E. Hoff, S.J.: Death (July 23, 2004) and Funeral (Box 47, Folder 1)
      This folder contains: 1. Funeral guest list, program and obituary card; 2. Planning agenda; 3. Funeral expenses.
    - James E. Hoff, S.J.: Death (July 23, 2004) and Funeral (Box 47, Folder 2)
      This folder contains various articles about Fr. Hoff.
    - James E. Hoff, S.J.: Death (July 23, 2004) and Funeral (Box 47, Folder 3)
      This folder contains correspondence by Fr. Michael Graham, S.J. relating to the death of Fr. Hoff.
    - James E. Hoff, S.J.: Death (July 23, 2004) and Funeral (Box 47, Folder 4)
      This folder contains correspondence by Michael Graham, S.J. concerning the death of Fr. Hoff. Other materials are also included.
    - James E. Hoff, S.J.: Death (July 23 2004) and Funeral (Box 47, Folder 5)
      This folder contains letters, cards, and memorials in honor of Fr. Hoff.
    - Oversized Materials: Hoff Funeral Displays, 2004
      These materials are housed separately in the Xavier University Archives map case.
    - Hoff Academic Garb, 1991-2004 (Box 47-A)
      Two academic caps worn by Fr. Hoff.
      These items are housed separately in Xavier University Archives.
    - Hoff Academic Garb, 1991-2004 (Piece 1)
      The academic gown and hood worn by Fr. Hoff.
- 21st Century Xavier Presidents, 2000-2013
  - Michael J. Graham, S.J., 2000-2014
    - Inauguration (September 8, 2001) (Folder 1), 2000-2001 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      This folder contains: 1. the announcement of Graham's appointment as president; 2. an inauguration exhibit; 3. the inauguration budget; 4. inauguration publicity; 5. inauguration local arrangements; and 6. inauguration student events.
    - Inauguration (September 8, 2001) (Folder 2) (Box 48, Folder 2)
      This folder contains inauguration invitations and information on the inauguration banquet.
    - Inauguration (September 8, 2001) (Folder 3) (Box 48, Folder 3)
      This folder contains: 1. the inauguration program; 2. the inauguration Academic Convocation program (September 11, 2001) and related materials.
    - Inauguration (September 8, 2001) (Box 48, Folder 4)
      This folder contains inauguration committee materials.
    - Listening Sessions, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      This folder contains information on Graham's "Listening Sessions" in the Spring Semester, 2001.
    - Newspaper Articles and Photos, 2000-2012 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      This folder contains newspaper articles and reports about Fr. Graham.
    - Speeches, 2001-2011; undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
      This folder contains various speeches by Fr. Graham, including his inauguration speech entitled "Scholars, Saints, and Citizen-Servants."
    - Correspondence, 1998-2013 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      This folder contains a very limited collection of correspondence by Fr. Graham.